<bill session="114" type="h" number="3427" updated="2017-06-02T21:31:05Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Payroll Fraud Prevention Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to ensure that employees are not misclassified as non-employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Payroll Fraud Prevention Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412607" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412642" joined="2015-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412657" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2016-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412600" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2015-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2015-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412613" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2015-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2015-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2015-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2015-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2015-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2015-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2015-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412644" joined="2015-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1896"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Payroll Fraud Prevention Act of 2015

 Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA) to require every person (including every employer and enterprise) that employs an employee or non-employee who performs labor or services, including through an entity such as a trust, estate, partnership, association, company, or corporation, to: (1) classify such individuals accurately as employees or non-employees; and (2) notify each new employee and new non-employee of his or her classification as an employee or non-employee, together with information concerning their legal rights.

Makes it unlawful for any person to: (1) discharge or otherwise discriminate against an individual (including an employee) who has opposed any practice, or filed a complaint or instituted any proceeding related to this Act, including with respect to an individual's status as an employee or non-employee; and (2) wrongly classify an employee as a non-employee.

Doubles the amount of liquidated damages for maximum hours, minimum wage, and notice of classification violations by an employer. Subjects a person who: (1) violates such requirements (including recordkeeping requirements) to a civil penalty of up to $1,100; or (2) repeatedly or willfully violates such requirements to a civil penalty of up to $5,000 for each violation.

Directs the Department of Labor (DOL) to establish a single webpage on its website that summarizes the rights of employees and non-employees under the FLSA and this Act.

Amends the Social Security Act to require, as a condition for a federal grant for the administration of state unemployment compensation, for the state's unemployment compensation law to include requirements for: (1) auditing programs that identify employers that have not registered under the state law or that are paying unreported compensation where the effect is to exclude employees from unemployment compensation coverage, and (2) establishing administrative penalties for misclassifying employees or paying unreported unemployment compensation to employees.

Requires any office, administration, or division of DOL to report any misclassification of an employee by a person subject to the FLSA that it discovers to the DOL Wage and Hour Division (WHD). Authorizes the WHD to report such information to the Internal Revenue Service.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
