<bill session="114" type="h" number="5819" updated="2017-06-02T22:12:56Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vote By Mail Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to allow all eligible voters to vote by mail in Federal elections, to amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to provide for automatic voter registration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Vote By Mail Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2016-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2016-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1129"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="114" type="s" number="3214"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Vote by Mail Act of 2016

This bill amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to:

 prohibit a state from imposing any additional conditions or requirements on the eligibility of an individual to cast a vote in a federal election by mail, except to the extent of setting a deadline for returning the ballot to the appropriate state or local election official; and require each state to mail ballots, not later than two weeks before the election, and at no charge, to individuals registered to vote in it. The National Voter Registration Act of 1993 is amended to revise requirements for simultaneous application for voter registration and for a motor vehicle driver's license to authorize automatic voter registration of individuals through state motor vehicle authorities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
