<bill session="114" type="h" number="5962" updated="2017-07-20T13:49:58Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SIMPLE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining Income-driven, Manageable Payments on Loans for Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for the automatic recertification of income for income-driven repayment plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SIMPLE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412501"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412651" joined="2016-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412613" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412672" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2016-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2016-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5167-5168"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Streamlining Income-driven, Manageable Payments on Loans for Education Act or the SIMPLE Act

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise the process for enrolling a borrower in federal student loan repayment plans when the borrower is delinquent on payments for student loans under the Direct Loan program. Specifically, the Department of Education (ED) may use the tax information of certain delinquent borrowers for purposes of calculating their income-driven repayment plan options. ED must notify those borrowers about their delinquency and repayment plan options. ED must also establish and implement procedures for automatically recertifying the income of certain delinquent borrowers for the purpose of determining their repayment obligations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
