<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-06-19</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2015-06-19T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-12-03T16:31:44Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to:</p> <ul> <li>establish PreCheck application enrollment standards to add multiple private sector application capabilities for the TSA PreCheck program to increase the public's enrollment access to such program; </li> <li> coordinate with interested parties to deploy TSA-approved ready-to-market private sector solutions that meet such standards, make available additional PreCheck enrollment capabilities, and offer secure online and mobile enrollment opportunities; </li> <li> partner with the private sector to collect biographic and biometric identification information via secure mobile enrollment platforms to reduce the need to travel to enrollment centers; and </li> <li> ensure that any biometric and biographic information is collected in a manner which ensures privacy and data security protections.</li> </ul> <p>The TSA must: </p> <ul> <li> develop and implement a process for approving private sector marketing of the program and a strategy for partnering with the private sector to encourage enrollment;</li> <li>report on any PreCheck fees collected in excess of the costs of administering such program;</li> <li> coordinate with the heads of appropriate Department of Homeland Security (DHS) components to leverage DHS-held data and technologies to verify the citizenship of individuals who want to enroll;</li> <li>partner with the private sector to use advanced biometrics and NIST 800-63-2 identity proofing standards to facilitate enrollment;</li> <li> ensure that TSA PreCheck screening lanes are available during peak and high-volume travel times at airports to enrolled individuals;</li> <li>provide for expedited screening at standard screening lanes during times when PreCheck screening lanes are closed; and</li> <li> ensure that enrolled individuals are vetted through the TSA's terrorist screening databases and develop effective recurrent vetting capabilities for disqualifying criminal offenses. </li> </ul>]]></text>
        </item>
        <item>
          <versionCode>17</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-07-22</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2015-07-22T11:56:04Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-12-03T22:00:06Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
          <name>Reported to House with amendment(s)</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to publish application enrollment standards to add multiple private sector application capabilities for the TSA PreCheck program to increase the public's enrollment access to such program.</p> <p>Upon publication of such standards, the TSA must:</p> <ul> <li> coordinate with interested parties to deploy TSA-approved ready-to-market private sector solutions that meet such standards, make available additional enrollment capabilities, and offer secure online and mobile enrollment opportunities; </li> <li> partner with the private sector to collect biographic and biometric identification information via secure mobile enrollment platforms to reduce the need for passengers to travel to enrollment centers; </li> <li> ensure that any biometric and biographic information is collected in a manner that ensures privacy and data security protections; </li> <li> ensure that an individual who has started an enrollment application with a single identification verification at one location will be able to save such application on any platform and be able to return to submit a second identification verification; </li> <li> ensure that any enrollment expansion using a private sector risk assessment is determined to be equivalent to a fingerprint-based criminal history records check conducted through the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</li> <li> develop and implement a process for approving private sector marketing of the TSA PreCheck program and a strategy for partnering with the private sector to encourage enrollment; and </li> <li> report on any PreCheck fees collected in excess of the costs of administering such program, including recommendations for using such amounts to support marketing of such program.</li> </ul> <p>The TSA is required to:</p> <ul> <li>coordinate with the heads of appropriate Department of Homeland Security (DHS) components to leverage DHS-held data and technologies to verify the citizenship of individuals enrolling in the program;</li> <li> partner with the private sector to use advanced biometrics and NIST 800-63-2 identity proofing standards to facilitate enrollment;</li> <li> ensure that TSA PreCheck screening lanes are available during peak and high-volume travel times at airports to enrolled individuals;</li> <li> provide for expedited screening at standard screening lanes during times when PreCheck screening lanes are closed; and</li> <li> initiate an assessment of the security vulnerabilities in the vetting process for the program that includes an evaluation of whether subjecting PreCheck participants to recurrent fingerprint-based criminal history records checks, in addition to recurrent checks against the terrorist watchlist, could be done in a cost-effective manner to strengthen the security of the program. </li> </ul>]]></text>
        </item>
        <item>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2015-07-27T15:29:47Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-12-03T22:13:11Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to publish application enrollment standards to add multiple private sector application capabilities for the TSA PreCheck program to increase the public's enrollment access to such program.</p> <p>Upon publication of such standards, the TSA must:</p> <ul> <li> coordinate with interested parties to deploy TSA-approved ready-to-market private sector solutions that meet such standards, make available additional enrollment capabilities, and offer secure online and mobile enrollment opportunities; </li> <li> partner with the private sector to collect biographic and biometric identification information via secure mobile enrollment platforms to reduce the need for passengers to travel to enrollment centers; </li> <li> ensure that any biometric and biographic information is collected in a manner that is comparable with the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) standards and that ensures privacy and data security protections, including that applicants' personally identifiable information is collected, retained, used, and shared in a manner consistent with the Privacy Act of 1974; </li> <li> ensure that an individual who has started an enrollment application with a single identification verification at one location will be able to save such application on any platform and be able to return to submit a second identification verification; </li> <li> ensure that any enrollment expansion using a private sector risk assessment is determined to be equivalent to a fingerprint-based criminal history records check conducted through the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</li> <li> develop and implement a process for approving private sector marketing of the TSA PreCheck program and a strategy for partnering with the private sector to encourage enrollment; and </li> <li> report on any PreCheck fees collected in excess of the costs of administering such program, including recommendations for using such amounts to support marketing of such program.</li> </ul> <p>The TSA is required to:</p> <ul> <li>coordinate with the heads of appropriate Department of Homeland Security (DHS) components to leverage DHS-held data and technologies to verify the citizenship of individuals enrolling in the program;</li> <li> partner with the private sector to use advanced biometrics and standards comparable to NIST standards to facilitate enrollment;</li> <li> ensure that TSA PreCheck screening lanes are available during peak and high-volume travel times at airports to enrolled individuals;</li> <li> provide for expedited screening at standard screening lanes during times when PreCheck screening lanes are closed; and</li> <li> initiate an assessment of the security vulnerabilities in the vetting process for the program that includes an evaluation of whether subjecting PreCheck participants to recurrent fingerprint-based criminal history records checks, in addition to recurrent checks against the terrorist watchlist, could be done in a cost-effective manner to strengthen the security of the program. </li> </ul>]]></text>
        </item>
        <item>
          <versionCode>01</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2016-03-07</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-03-07T14:06:42Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-04-15T13:44:21Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
          <name>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to continue to administer the Precheck Program (trusted traveler program).</p> <p>(Sec. 4) TSA shall publish application enrollment standards that add multiple private sector application capabilities for the PreCheck program to increase the public's enrollment access to such program.</p> <p>Upon publication of such standards, the TSA must:</p> <ul> <li> coordinate with interested parties to deploy TSA-approved ready-to-market private sector solutions that meet such standards, make available additional enrollment capabilities, and offer secure online and mobile enrollment opportunities; </li> <li> partner with the private sector to collect biographic and biometric identification information via mobile enrollment platforms to increase enrollment flexibility and minimize the amount of travel to enrollment centers for applicants; </li> <li> ensure that any biometric and biographic information is collected in a manner that is comparable with National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) standards and that protects privacy and data security, including that any personally identifiable information is collected, retained, used, and shared in a manner consistent with the Privacy Act of 1974; </li> <li> ensure that the enrollment process is streamlined and flexible to allow an individual to provide additional information to complete enrollment and verify identity; </li> <li> ensure that any enrollment expansion using a private sector risk assessment is determined to be equivalent to a fingerprint-based criminal history records check conducted through the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</li> <li> develop and implement a continual process for approving private sector marketing of the PreCheck program and a long-term strategy for partnering with the private sector to encourage enrollment; and </li> <li> report on any PreCheck Program application fees collected in excess of the costs of administering the program, including assessment of its feasibility and recommendations for using such amounts to support its marketing.</li> </ul> <p>The TSA shall:</p> <ul> <li>coordinate with the heads of appropriate Department of Homeland Security (DHS) components to leverage DHS-held data and technologies to verify the citizenship of individuals enrolling in the program;</li> <li> partner with the private sector to use biometrics and authentication standards such as those developed by NIST to facilitate enrollment;</li> <li>consider leveraging existing airport resources to conduct fingerprint and background checks to expedite identity verification;</li> <li> ensure that PreCheck Program screening lanes are available during peak and high-volume travel times at airports to enrolled individuals;</li> <li> provide for expedited screening at standard screening lanes during times when PreCheck Program screening lanes are closed; and</li> <li> initiate an assessment to identify security vulnerabilities in the vetting process for the program, including whether subjecting PreCheck Program participants to recurrent fingerprint-based criminal history records checks, in addition to recurrent checks against the terrorist watchlist, could be done in a cost-effective manner to strengthen the security of the program. </li> </ul>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <title>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <title>H.R. 2843, TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
        <pubDate>2015-07-20T14:03:42Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/50408</url>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>H.R. 2843, TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
        <pubDate>2015-12-23T13:31:17Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51103</url>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>H.R. 2843, TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
        <pubDate>2016-03-09T18:06:00Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51359</url>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1804</lisID>
          <gpoId>8166</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>M001157</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <middleName>T.</middleName>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>10</district>
        <lastName>McCaul</lastName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-06-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>M001157</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. McCaul, Michael T. [R-TX-10]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
      <item>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1704</lisID>
          <bioguideId>R000575</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7788</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <middleName />
        <state>AL</state>
        <district>3</district>
        <lastName>Rogers</lastName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-06-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <bioguideId>R000575</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Rogers, Mike D. [R-AL-3]</fullName>
        <party>R</party>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <createDate>2015-06-20T08:49:17Z</createDate>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-02-24</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Transportation Security Administration Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</latestTitle>
        <number>3584</number>
      </item>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-12-16</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>DHS Reform and Improvement Act</latestTitle>
        <number>6381</number>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Katko, John [R-NY-24]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2264</lisID>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>K000386</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <lastName>Katko</lastName>
        <bioguideId>K000386</bioguideId>
        <byRequestType />
        <district>24</district>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName />
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>15</houseOfRepresentatives>
        <senate>5</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-07</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 383.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-07</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 114-223</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/senate-report/223</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-223.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 114-223</name>
            <url>http://tntwxavlp01.loc.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/senate-report/223</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-03-07</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-223.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-09</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-28</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:49:03</actionTime>
        <links />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:49:02</actionTime>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H5501</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-161/house-section/page/H5501</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H5501)</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:49:02</actionTime>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H5501</name>
            <url>http://tntwxavlp01.loc.gov/congressional-record/volume-161/house-section/page/H5501</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H5501)</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:42:05</actionTime>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 2843</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/2843</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2843.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:42:04</actionTime>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H5501-5502</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-161/house-section/page/H5501-5502</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H5501-5502)</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>16:42:02</actionTime>
        <links />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-27</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Mr. Katko moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-22</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 167.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-221</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/221</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-22</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-221.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 114-221</name>
            <url>http://tntwxavlp01.loc.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/house-report/221</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-22</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-221.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-25</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-25</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-23</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hshm07</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation Security Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-06-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-06-19</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-06-19</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <generalDebate>1</generalDebate>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <committeeReportOfABill>1</committeeReportOfABill>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <actionStageOverride>1</actionStageOverride>
        <placeholderTextForH>2</placeholderTextForH>
        <considerationByHouse>1</considerationByHouse>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <reportedToSenate>2</reportedToSenate>
        <orderedReported>1</orderedReported>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <amendments />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Aviation and airports</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Citizenship and naturalization</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Marketing and advertising</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Right of privacy</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Terrorism</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Travel and tourism</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <introducedDate>2015-06-19</introducedDate>
    <laws />
    <notes />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees />
          <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2016-03-07T23:32:09Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-12-09T15:00:00Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-07-28T19:53:30Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <name>Transportation Security Subcommittee</name>
              <systemCode>hshm07</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2015-06-23T16:45:06Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2015-07-22T19:27:18Z</date>
              <name>Reported by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-06-25T14:00:25Z</date>
              <name>Markup by</name>
            </item>
            <item>
              <date>2015-06-19T16:00:33Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 114-221</citation>
      </committeeReport>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 114-223</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-03-07</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 383.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. KATKO:H.R. 2843.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 3--To regulate Commerce withforeign Nations, and among the several States, and with theIndian Tribes; andArticle I, Section 8, Clause 18--To make all Laws whichshall be necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof.[Page H4546]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <billNumber>2843</billNumber>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <calendar>U00167</calendar>
        <number />
      </item>
      <item>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
        <number>0383</number>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <updateDate>2017-06-02T21:23:17Z</updateDate>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <title>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To require certain improvements in the Transportation Security Administration's PreCheck expedited screening program, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>TSA PreCheck Expansion Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <recordedVotes />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

