<bill session="114" type="h" number="5344" updated="2017-06-02T22:02:51Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organ Donation Clarification Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify that pilot programs that honor and reward organ donation are not preempted by Federal criminal law and that offering and accepting such benefits in accordance with a pilot program are not criminal acts.</title>
    <title type="display">Organ Donation Clarification Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2016-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2016-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2016-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2016-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Organ Donation Clarification Act of 2016

This bill allows the exchange of human organs for valuable consideration (anything of value) under pilot programs approved by the Department of Health and Human Services to measure the effect of removing disincentives or providing a noncash benefit that may increase organ availability. (Currently, exchanging human organs for valuable consideration is prohibited by the National Organ Transplant Act.)

In addition to reimbursements permitted in the National Organ Transplant Act, this bill declares that valuable consideration does not include:

 dependent care needs related to organ donation, medical expenses related to donation and all related follow-up care including preventive follow-up care and medication, paperwork or legal costs related to donation, or an insurance policy against the risk of death or disability as a result of donating an organ or the longer-term health effects of having donated an organ.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
