<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Coordinating Transportation Services for Transportation Disadvantaged Individuals Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To coordinate transportation services for transportation-disadvantaged individuals.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Coordinating Transportation Services for Transportation Disadvantaged Individuals Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <updateDate>2017-06-02T21:40:03Z</updateDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Aging</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Disability and paralysis</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public transit</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Roads and highways</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>State and local government operations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation programs funding</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <cosponsors />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <createDate>2015-11-20T10:16:05Z</createDate>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <title>Coordinating Transportation Services for Transportation Disadvantaged Individuals Act of 2015</title>
    <introducedDate>2015-11-19</introducedDate>
    <amendments />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. WEBSTER of Florida:H.R. 4082.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The authority granted Congress under Article 1, Section 8,Clause 3 and Clause 7 of the United States Constitutionestablish the basis for Congress to authorize surfacetransportation funding.[Page H8412]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <laws />
    <relatedBills />
    <recordedVotes />
    <billNumber>4082</billNumber>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
      <actionDate>2015-11-20</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2015-11-19</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2015-11-19T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-04-12T18:29:58Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Coordinating Transportation Services for Transportation Disadvantaged Individuals Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes in the Department of Transportation (DOT) the New Interagency Transportation Coordinating Council on Access and Mobility to coordinate transportation services to transportation-disadvantaged individuals (those who require the use of public transportation but have difficulty accessing it due to disability, income level, age, or veteran status) in a manner that is cost effective and efficient and that minimizes the fragmentation and duplication of such services.</p> <p>The Council shall: </p> <ul> <li>develop a strategic plan that identifies federal agency roles and responsibilities and measurable outcomes in coordinating such services; </li> <li>develop a joint cost-sharing policy among federal agencies with representatives on the Council that provides clear guidance to state and local governments regarding cost allocation; </li> <li>maintain an inventory of all federal programs that provide such services; and </li> <li>partner with State Transport Coordinating Commissions (STCCs) and aid them in coordinating such services. </li></ul> <p>A state must establish an STCC to coordinate transportation for transportation-disadvantaged individuals. An STCC shall:</p> <ul> <li>compile information on transportation operations for and needs of such individuals; </li> <li>establish statewide objectives for coordinating transportation services for such individuals; </li> <li>develop written policies and procedures for the coordination of government funding for such individuals; </li> <li>identify and pursue the elimination of barriers to transportation services; </li> <li>establish an information clearinghouse; </li> <li>assist communities in developing transportation systems designed to serve such individuals; </li> <li>verify that purchasing procedures aid the coordination of such services; </li> <li>verify that purchasing agencies purchase all trips within transportation systems that serve such individuals, unless they use more cost-effective alternative providers; and </li> <li>develop a strategic plan that addresses the transportation problems and needs of such individuals over a five-year period. </li></ul> <p>DOT must withhold 1% of the amount required to be apportioned to a state under specified federal-aid highway programs on the first day of each fiscal year beginning with FY2017 if the state does not meet this bill's requirements. </p> <p>Each federal agency shall keep an accounting of expenditures directly related to services for transportation-disadvantaged individuals. No federal agency may make capital investments for the purpose of providing the services.</p> <p>The bill terminates the Interagency Transportation Coordinating Council on Access and Mobility.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-11-20</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw12</systemCode>
          <name>Highways and Transit Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-11-19</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-11-19T14:32:30Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <name>Highways and Transit Subcommittee</name>
              <systemCode>hspw12</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2015-11-20T19:21:56Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>W000806</bioguideId>
        <state>FL</state>
        <lastName>Webster</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>W000806</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>7880</gpoId>
          <lisID>2002</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <district>10</district>
        <fullName>Rep. Webster, Daniel [R-FL-10]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Daniel</firstName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <notes />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

