<bill session="114" type="h" number="5214" updated="2017-06-02T21:57:48Z">
  <state datetime="2016-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Savings Accounts Offer Parents Plenty Of Reasons To Understand and Invest in Tuition Yearly Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CSA OPPORTUNITY Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act, the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, and the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 to require that the value of child's savings accounts be disregarded for the purpose of determining eligibility to receive benefits under such Acts; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CSA OPPORTUNITY Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2016-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2016-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2016-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2016-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Nutrition" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="473"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Children's Savings Accounts Offer Parents Plenty of Reasons to Understand and Invest in Tuition Yearly Act or the CSA OPPORTUNITY Act 

This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to direct a state receiving a TANF grant to disregard the value of any interest in, or distribution from, a qualified tuition program, as well as the value of a child's savings account, in determining individual or family TANF eligibility or the amount or type of assistance.

SSAct title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) is amended to exclude from an individual's resources for SSI eligibility or benefit purposes the value of any interest in, or distribution from, a qualified tuition program as well as the value of a child's savings account.

 The Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 is amended to direct the Department of Agriculture to exclude any child's savings accounts from resources for eligibility and benefit purposes under the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP, formerly the food stamp program).

 The Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 is amended to exclude from household income any child's savings accounts from resources for eligibility and benefit purposes under the low-income home energy assistance program.

 The bill prescribes penalties for noncompliance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
