<bill session="115" type="h" number="2356" updated="2017-06-29T07:16:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Managing Your Data Against Telecom Abuses Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Managing Your Data Against Telecom Abuses Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MY DATA Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MY DATA Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect broadband users from unfair or deceptive practices relating to privacy or data security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">MY DATA Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2017-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412684" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2017-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="115" type="s" number="964"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Managing Your Data Against Telecom Abuses Act of 2017 or the MY DATA Act of 2017

This bill prohibits providers of Internet broadband services or of Internet content, applications, or devices from using unfair or deceptive acts or practices relating to privacy or data security.

The Federal Trade Commission (FTC), after consulting with the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), may promulgate regulations to carry out such prohibition.

The FTC may also enforce this bill against common carriers regulated by the FCC under the Communications Act of 1934 and nonprofit organizations. (Currently, common carriers regulated under the Communications Act are exempt from the FTC's enforcement authority and nonprofit organizations are subject to FTC enforcement only if they provide substantial economic benefit to their for-profit members.)

A state may bring a civil action in federal court to enforce such prohibition.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
