<bill session="114" type="h" number="6345" updated="2017-06-02T22:17:27Z">
  <state datetime="2016-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TPS Reform Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to modify the procedure to designate a foreign state, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">TPS Reform Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412655" joined="2016-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412605" joined="2016-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2016-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2016-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2016-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2016-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-11-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">TPS Reform Act of 2016

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise the criteria for designation of a foreign state as eligible to have its citizens be given temporary protected status (TPS) in the United States.

Such revisions include the following: (1) such a foreign state shall be designated by an Act of Congress rather than by the Department of Justice; (2) such Act must find that an environmental disaster in such a foreign state is immediately life-threatening; (3) such Act may provide for early termination of a foreign state's designation; (4) such Act shall include an estimate of the number of a foreign state's nationals who are TPS eligible, their U.S. immigration status, and a time period for the effectiveness of the designation of not more than 18 months; and (5) an alien lacking lawful immigration status shall be ineligible for TPS.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
