<bill session="114" type="h" number="3782" updated="2017-06-02T21:36:23Z">
  <state datetime="2015-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prohibiting Detention of Youth Status Offenders Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to eliminate the use of valid court orders to secure lockup of status offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Prohibiting Detention of Youth Status Offenders Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412517"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2015-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412562" joined="2015-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2015-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2016-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2015-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-10-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7169"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1850"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-10-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Prohibiting Detention of Youth Status Offenders Act of 2015

This bill amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, with respect to the detention of a juvenile status offender (a juvenile arrested for an offense that would not be a crime if committed by an adult) who violates a valid court order, to require the court placing such juvenile in detention to issue a written order that: (1) identifies the valid court order that has been violated; (2) specifies the factual basis for determining that there is reasonable cause to believe that the juvenile has violated such order; (3) includes findings of fact to support a determination that there is no appropriate less restrictive alternative available to placing the juvenile in a secure detention or correctional facility, with due consideration to the best interest of the juvenile; (4) specifies the length of time, not to exceed three days, that the juvenile may remain in such facility and includes a plan for the juvenile's release; and (5) may not be renewed or extended. It provides that a juvenile status offender may only be detained once in any six-month period. The bill eliminates, not later than one year after the enactment of this Act, the use of valid court orders to provide secure lockup of juvenile status offenders.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
