<bill session="114" type="s" number="2028" updated="2017-06-02T23:28:24Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Lending Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Credit Union Act, to advance the ability of credit unions to promote small business growth and economic development opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Lending Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412492"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2015-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2015-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2015-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2015-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2016-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2015-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2015-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1188"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-09-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Lending Enhancement Act of 2015

 Amends the Federal Credit Union Act to prohibit an insured credit union from making any member business loan that would result in the total amount of such loans outstanding at that credit union at any one time exceeding either: (1) 1.75 times the actual net worth of the credit union, or (2) 12.25% of the total assets of the credit union.

Authorizes the National Credit Union Administration Board to approve an application by an insured credit union to make one or more member business loans that would result in a total amount of such loans outstanding at any one time of up to 27.5 % of the total assets of the credit union, if the credit union meets specified safety and soundness criteria. Prohibits an insured credit union that has made such a member business loan but that is not well capitalized from making any new member business loans until it becomes well capitalized and obtains Board approval.

Directs the Board to develop a tiered approval process, including lending standards, under which an insured credit union gradually increases the amount of member business lending in a manner that is consistent with safe and sound operations.

Directs the Government Accountability Office to study the status of member business lending by insured credit unions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
