<bill session="114" type="h" number="5470" updated="2017-06-02T22:04:34Z">
  <state datetime="2016-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Mass Killings By Violent Terrorists Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to require a criminal background check to be conducted before a federally licensed firearms importer, manufacturer, or dealer may transfer a large capacity ammunition feeding device to a non-licensee, and to prohibit a semiautomatic assault weapon or large capacity ammunition feeding device from being so transferred until the Attorney General has verified that the prospective transferee has truthfully answered questions about whether the prospective transferee has been contacted recently by Federal law enforcement authorities.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Mass Killings By Violent Terrorists Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412607" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2016-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2016-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2016-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412595" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412638" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2016-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2016-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2016-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1075"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Mass Killings By Violent Terrorists Act

This bill amends the federal criminal code to&#160;prohibit a federally licensed firearms dealer, importer, or manufacturer from transferring, to a person who is a non-licensee, a large capacity ammunition feeding device, unless: (1)&#160;the licensee has conducted a criminal background check of the person, and (2)&#160;the Department of Justice (DOJ) has verified the truthfulness of certain written responses given by the person with respect to recent contacts by federal law enforcement authorities.

In addition, the bill prohibits a federally licensed firearms dealer, importer, or manufacturer from transferring, to a person who is a non-licensee, a semiautomatic weapon (for which a criminal background check is already required under current law), unless DOJ has verified the truthfulness of the person's written responses with respect to recent contacts by federal law enforcement authorities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
