<bill session="114" type="hr" number="585" updated="2017-06-02T19:32:49Z">
  <state datetime="2016-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding an Interstate 73 corridor transportation compact.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding an Interstate 73 corridor transportation compact.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412484"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412607" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412605" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412658" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412485" joined="2016-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412550" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2016-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412572" joined="2016-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-01-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the entering into of an agreement or compact by two or more states for cooperative effort and mutual assistance would be beneficial to the development of an Interstate 73 corridor.

 Such an agreement may incorporate the following elements to the extent that they are consistent with federal law:

 the study, development, and promotion of a plan for the design, construction, financing, and operation of such corridor through South Carolina, North Carolina, Virginia, West Virginia, Ohio, and Michigan; coordination of efforts to establish a common legal framework in all the signatory states to authorize and facilitate design, construction, financing, and operation of such corridor or through public-private partnerships; advocacy for federal funding to support the establishment of such corridor; making available to the corridor project funding and resources that are or may be appropriated by the signatory states and allocated for that purpose; and doing all things necessary or convenient to facilitate and coordinate the corridor's design, construction, financing, and operation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
