<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Violence Against Women Veterans Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to improve the provision of services and benefits from the Department of Veterans Affairs for veterans who experience domestic violence or sexual assault, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Violence Against Women Veterans Act</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <updateDate>2017-06-03T00:08:03Z</updateDate>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects />
        <policyArea>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <cosponsors />
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <createDate>2016-09-29T05:34:48Z</createDate>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <title>Violence Against Women Veterans Act</title>
    <introducedDate>2016-09-28</introducedDate>
    <amendments />
    <laws />
    <relatedBills />
    <recordedVotes />
    <billNumber>3434</billNumber>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2016-09-28T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-12-15T23:02:34Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Violence Against Women Veterans Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a program to assist veterans that have experienced or are experiencing domestic violence or sexual assault in accessing benefits from the VA, including by coordinating access to medical treatment centers, housing assistance, and other benefits. The VA shall carry out the program in partnership with specified health care or other service providers that serve domestic violence or sexual assault victims.</p> <p>The VA may: (1) conduct training for community-based domestic violence or sexual assault service providers on identifying veterans who have been victims, coordinating with local VA service providers, and connecting veterans with appropriate VA housing, mental health, medical, and other financial assistance or benefits; and (2) provide assistance to service providers to ensure veterans access to domestic violence and sexual assault emergency services.</p> <p>The VA may establish local coordinators to provide outreach under such program and ensure that each coordinator is knowledgeable about:</p> <ul> <li> the dynamics of domestic violence and sexual assault, including safety concerns, legal protections, and the need for confidential services; </li> <li> veteran eligibility for VA services and benefits relevant to recovery from domestic violence and sexual assault; and </li> <li> local community resources addressing domestic violence and sexual assault. </li> </ul> <p> Each coordinator shall assist domestic violence shelters and rape crisis centers in providing services to veterans. </p> <p>The VA shall: (1) establish a national task force to develop a comprehensive national program to address domestic violence and sexual assault among veterans, and (2) conduct a national baseline study to examine the scope of the problem of domestic violence and sexual assault among veterans and spouses of veterans.</p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <senate>2</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <committeeReports />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2016-09-28T20:30:54Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <party>D</party>
        <byRequestType />
        <bioguideId>S001181</bioguideId>
        <state>NH</state>
        <lastName>Shaheen</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>1901</lisID>
          <gpoId>8276</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>S001181</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <fullName>Sen. Shaheen, Jeanne [D-NH]</fullName>
        <middleName />
        <firstName>Jeanne</firstName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <notes />
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

