<bill session="114" type="h" number="3190" updated="2017-06-02T21:28:06Z">
  <state datetime="2015-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PREPARE Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preparedness and Risk Management for Extreme Weather Patterns Assuring Resilience and Effectiveness Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to enhance the Federal Government's planning and preparation for extreme weather, and the Federal Government's dissemination of best practices to respond to extreme weather, thereby increasing resilience, improving regional coordination, and mitigating the financial risk to the Federal Government from such extreme weather.</title>
    <title type="display">PREPARE Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412607" joined="2015-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2015-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2015-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2016-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2016-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2015-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412616" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2015-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2016-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2015-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2015-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-07-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Preparedness and Risk Management for Extreme Weather Patterns Assuring Resilience and Effectiveness Act of 2015 or the PREPARE Act of 2015

 This bill directs the President to establish the Interagency Council on Extreme Weather Resilience, Preparedness, and Risk Management (Council). The Council shall:

 establish government-wide goals and priorities for, and develop, recommend, coordinate, and track implementation of priority interagency federal government actions related to, extreme weather resilience, preparedness, and risk management; support regional, state, local, and tribal action to assess extreme weather-related vulnerabilities and cost effectively increase extreme weather resilience, preparedness, and risk management of communities, critical economic sectors, natural and built infrastructure, and natural resources; facilitate the integration of meteorological and extreme weather science; assess the specific recommendations relating to extreme weather in all relevant provisions of the Government Accountability Office's High-Risk Series, identify the feasibility of revising federal programs to implement such recommendations, and develop a plan to address such recommendations; develop or adopt a framework for evaluating the progress and success of extreme weather resilience, preparedness, and risk management-related efforts that is complementary to any national indicator system developed as part of the National Climate Assessment; develop or adopt performance metrics that allow tracking of the actions taken and progress made toward meeting and implementing the established government-wide goals and priorities; provide recommendations to the Council on Environmental Quality and OMB on how agencies should update agency extreme weather plans and remove barriers to state and local extreme weather resilience, preparedness, and risk management in agency regulations, guidance, and policy; make information available online for tracking implementation of agency extreme weather plans and government-wide goals and priorities and on recommendations relating to extreme weather in all relevant High-Risk Series provisions; issue guidance to agencies on developing agency extreme weather plans and agency regulations, guidance, and policies to remove barriers to state and local extreme weather resilience; designate one or more agencies to establish a website that provides information on risks related to extreme weather, preparedness, resilience, and risk management to support state, local, tribal, and private decisionmakers; and publish biannually an inventory of all regional agency offices, centers, and programs that assist with extreme weather preparedness and risk management at the state or local level. Each agency shall submit biannually to OMB and to the Council a comprehensive plan that integrates consideration of extreme weather into its operations and overall mission objectives. OMB shall consolidate and submit such plans to Congress.

Annual agency performance plans shall include the most recent agency extreme weather plan.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
