<bill session="114" type="s" number="3504" updated="2017-07-20T13:50:11Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating High-Quality Results and Outcomes Necessary to Improve Chronic (CHRONIC) Care Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to implement Medicare payment policies designed to improve management of chronic disease, streamline care coordination, and improve quality outcomes without adding to the deficit.</title>
    <title type="display">Creating High-Quality Results and Outcomes Necessary to Improve Chronic (CHRONIC) Care Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2016-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2016-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Creating High-Quality Results and Outcomes Necessary to Improve Chronic (CHRONIC) Care Act of 2016

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to:

 extend the Independence at Home demonstration program; modify&#160;provisions regarding access to home dialysis therapy under Medicare and special needs plans under Medicare Advantage (MA); expand testing of the MA Value-Based Insurance Design test model; allow an MA plan to provide additional telehealth benefits to enrollees and, to chronically ill enrollees, certain supplemental health care&#160;benefits; modify other provisions regarding the use of telehealth services; allow prospective, voluntary&#160;assignment of Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries to accountable care organizations (ACOs); and allow ACOs to operate beneficiary incentive programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
