<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <billNumber>1616</billNumber>
    <billType>S</billType>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2015-06-18</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish an Office of Federal Charge Card Analytics and Review (OFCCAR) for improving the use and oversight of purchase and travel card transactions by federal agencies and programs, including for purposes of: (1) identifying and preventing improper payments and other inappropriate use of purchase and travel cards that do not conform with federal or agency purchase laws, policies, rules, or best practices; and (2) determining opportunities for strategic sourcing (defined as analyzing and modifying a federal agency's spending patterns to better leverage its purchasing power, reduce costs, and improve overall performance).</p> <p>Makes the OFCCAR responsible for: (1) the review of purchase and travel card transaction data of all federal agencies, and (2) the establishment of a library of analytics tools and data sources for use by all federal agencies.</p> <p>Requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to issue guidance on improving information sharing by government agencies, including by: (1) requiring relevant officials at federal agencies to identify high-risk merchants and communicate that information to the appropriate level of administration within the agencies; (2) ensuring that appropriate officials at federal agencies review the reports issued by charge card-issuing contractors of potential fraudulent or otherwise inappropriate activity; and (3) providing for the appropriate sharing of information related to potential fraudulent transactions, fraud schemes, and high risk merchants with the OFCCAR and the appropriate federal officials.</p> <p>Requires the GSA and the OMB to establish an interagency task force to develop and share best practices, which shall: (1) cover rules, edits, and task order or contract modifications related to charge card-issuing contractors; and (2) include the review of purchase and travel card transaction data of all federal agencies for the purpose of determining strategic sourcing opportunities.</p>]]></text>
          <name>Introduced in Senate</name>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2015-10-05T19:44:29Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2015-06-18T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2015-12-08</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Reported to Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish an Office of Federal Charge Card Analytics and Review (OFCCAR) for improving the use and oversight of purchase and travel card transactions by federal agencies and programs, including for purposes of: (1) identifying and preventing improper payments and other inappropriate use of purchase and travel cards that do not conform with federal or agency purchase laws, policies, rules, or best practices; and (2) determining opportunities for strategic sourcing (defined as analyzing and modifying a federal agency's spending patterns to better leverage its purchasing power, reduce costs, and improve overall performance).</p> <p>The OFCCAR is responsible for: (1) the review of purchase and travel card transaction data of all federal agencies, and (2) the establishment of a library of analytics tools and data sources for use by all federal agencies.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Office of Management and Budget (OMB) must issue guidance on improving information sharing by government agencies, including by: (1) requiring relevant officials at federal agencies to identify high-risk merchants and communicate that information to the appropriate level of administration within the agencies; (2) ensuring that appropriate officials at federal agencies review the reports issued by charge card-issuing contractors of potential fraudulent or otherwise inappropriate activity; and (3) providing for the appropriate sharing of information related to potential fraudulent transactions, fraud schemes, and high risk merchants with the OFCCAR and the appropriate federal officials.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The GSA and the OMB must establish and co-chair an interagency task force to develop and share best practices, which shall: (1) cover rules, edits, and task order or contract modifications related to charge card-issuing contractors; and (2) include the review of purchase and travel card transaction data of all federal agencies for the purpose of determining strategic sourcing opportunities.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The GSA shall report to Congress on this Act's implementation, including the metrics used in determining whether the analytic and investigatory efforts have: (1) reduced, or contributed to the reduction of, improper payments; or (2) improved strategic sourcing.</p> <p>Each executive agency that issues and uses purchase cards and convenience checks shall report on its activities to implement this Act.</p>]]></text>
          <name>Reported to Senate without amendment</name>
          <versionCode>80</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-01-08T16:21:00Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2015-12-08T14:11:58Z</updateDate>
        </item>
        <item>
          <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
          <actionDesc>Passed Senate amended</actionDesc>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to develop a strategy to expand the use of data analytics in managing government purchase and travel charge card programs for the purpose of:</p> <ul> <li> identifying examples or patterns of questionable transactions and developing enhanced tools and methods for agency use in identifying questionable purchase and travel card transactions and in recovering improper payments made with purchase and travel cards; </li> <li> identifying potential opportunities for agencies to further leverage administrative process streamlining and cost reduction from purchase and travel card use; </li> <li> developing a set of purchase and travel card metrics and benchmarks for high risk activities, which shall assist agencies in identifying potential emphasis areas for their purchase and travel card management and oversight activities; and </li> <li> developing a plan to create a library of analytics tools and data sources for use by federal agencies. </ul> <p>The bill defines: (1) &quot;questionable transaction&quot; as a charge card transaction that, from initial card data, appears to be high risk and that may be improper; and (2) &quot;strategic sourcing&quot; as analyzing and modifying a federal agency's spending patterns to better leverage its purchasing power, reduce costs, and improve overall performance.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The OMB must issue guidance on improving information sharing by government agencies, including by: (1) requiring relevant officials at federal agencies to identify high-risk activities and communicate that information to the appropriate management levels within the agencies; (2) requiring that appropriate officials at federal agencies review the reports issued by charge card-issuing banks on questionable transaction activity, including transactions that occur with high risk activities, and suspicious timing or amounts of cash withdrawals or advances; and (3) providing for the appropriate sharing of information related to potential questionable transactions, fraud schemes, and high risk activities with GSA's Office of Charge Card Management and the appropriate federal agency officials. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The GSA and the OMB must establish a purchase and travel charge card data management group to develop and share best practices, which shall: (1) cover rules, edits, and task order or contract modifications related to charge card-issuing banks; and (2) include the review of accounts payable information and purchase and travel card transaction data of agencies for the purpose of identifying potential strategic sourcing and other additional opportunities for which the charge cards or related payment products could be used as a payment method.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The GSA shall report to Congress on this Act's implementation, including the metrics used in determining whether the analytic and benchmarking efforts have reduced, or contributed to the reduction of, questionable or improper payments as well as improved utilization of card-based payment products.</p> <p>Each executive agency that issues and uses purchase cards and convenience checks shall report to the OMB on activities to implement this Act. The OMB shall submit to Congress a consolidated report of agency activities to implement this Act.</p> <p>The GSA shall report to Congress identifying and exploring further potential savings opportunities for government agencies under the federal charge card programs.</p>]]></text>
          <name>Passed Senate amended</name>
          <versionCode>35</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2016-02-24T19:12:17Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <updateDate>2015-12-16T13:54:34Z</updateDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>DE</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <byRequestType />
        <firstName>THOMAS</firstName>
        <lastName>CARPER</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>179</lisID>
          <gpoId>8283</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <fullName>Sen. Carper, Thomas R. [D-DE]</fullName>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Office of Management and Budget (OMB)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Transportation costs</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-06-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <state>IA</state>
        <middleName>ERNEST</middleName>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>CHARLES</firstName>
        <lastName>GRASSLEY</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>457</lisID>
          <gpoId>8316</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>G000386</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>G000386</bioguideId>
        <party>R</party>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Sen. Grassley, Chuck [R-IA]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-06-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <state>MO</state>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Claire</firstName>
        <lastName>McCaskill</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>8252</gpoId>
          <bioguideId>M001170</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1820</lisID>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>M001170</bioguideId>
        <party>D</party>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Sen. McCaskill, Claire [D-MO]</fullName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-06-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <state>WI</state>
        <middleName />
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <firstName>Ron</firstName>
        <lastName>Johnson</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2086</lisID>
          <bioguideId>J000293</bioguideId>
          <gpoId>8355</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>J000293</bioguideId>
        <party>R</party>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <fullName>Sen. Johnson, Ron [R-WI]</fullName>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2015-08-13T15:28:51Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/50733</url>
        <title>S. 1616, Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number>0315</number>
        <calendar>Senate Calendar of Business</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <latestAction>
      <links />
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
      <actionDate>2015-12-17</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <notes />
    <introducedDate>2015-06-18</introducedDate>
    <createDate>2015-06-19T09:13:38Z</createDate>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <title>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed Senate</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles Senate</parentTitleType>
        <title>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>A bill to provide for the identification and prevention of improper payments and the identification of strategic sourcing opportunities by reviewing and analyzing the use of Federal agency charge cards.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <parentTitleType />
        <title>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <title>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</title>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 114-174</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-12-17T21:05:02Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees />
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported by</name>
              <date>2015-12-08T16:29:32Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Markup by</name>
              <date>2015-06-24T14:00:00Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2015-06-18T16:18:46Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <recordedVotes />
    <laws />
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>2</houseOfRepresentatives>
        <senate>10</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-12-17</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
          <name>Oversight and Government Reform Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-17</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionTime>11:06:35</actionTime>
        <links />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H14000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-12-17</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Received in the House.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>S8728-8729</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-161/senate-section/page/S8728-8729</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR S8728-8729)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-08</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 315.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-08</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 114-174</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/senate-report/174</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 114-174.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>report No. 114-174</name>
            <url>http://tntwxavlp01.loc.gov/congressional-report/114th-congress/senate-report/174</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-12-08</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 114-174.</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-24</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-18</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
          <code>0</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <links />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-06-18</actionDate>
        <committee />
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <passedSenate>1</passedSenate>
        <passedAgreedToInSenate>1</passedAgreedToInSenate>
        <placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>1</placedOnCalendarGeneralOrders>
        <reportedToSenate>2</reportedToSenate>
        <measureLaidBeforeSenate>1</measureLaidBeforeSenate>
        <orderedReported>1</orderedReported>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <introducedInSenate>1</introducedInSenate>
        <receivedInTheHouse>1</receivedInTheHouse>
        <sentToHouse>1</sentToHouse>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <amendments>
      <amendment>
        <number>2930</number>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
          <text>Amendment SA 2930 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <description />
        <purpose>In the nature of a substitute.</purpose>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>SAMDT</type>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <titles />
        <amendments>
          <count>0</count>
        </amendments>
        <submittedDate>2015-12-16T05:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <purpose>In the nature of a substitute.</purpose>
        <amendedAmendment />
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <fullName>Sen. Carper, Thomas R. [D-DE]</fullName>
            <firstName>THOMAS</firstName>
            <party>D</party>
            <lastName>CARPER</lastName>
            <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
            <middleName>R.</middleName>
            <state>DE</state>
            <identifiers>
              <lisID>179</lisID>
              <gpoId>8283</gpoId>
              <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
            </identifiers>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <cosponsors>
          <currentCount>3</currentCount>
          <totalCount>3</totalCount>
          <item>
            <party>R</party>
            <sponsorshipDate>2015-12-16</sponsorshipDate>
            <bioguideId>G000386</bioguideId>
            <state>IA</state>
            <lastName>GRASSLEY</lastName>
            <identifiers>
              <lisID>457</lisID>
              <gpoId>8316</gpoId>
              <bioguideId>G000386</bioguideId>
            </identifiers>
            <fullName>Sen. Grassley, Chuck [R-IA]</fullName>
            <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
            <middleName>ERNEST</middleName>
            <firstName>CHARLES</firstName>
            <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
          </item>
          <item>
            <party>D</party>
            <sponsorshipDate>2015-12-16</sponsorshipDate>
            <bioguideId>M001170</bioguideId>
            <state>MO</state>
            <lastName>McCaskill</lastName>
            <identifiers>
              <gpoId>8252</gpoId>
              <bioguideId>M001170</bioguideId>
              <lisID>1820</lisID>
            </identifiers>
            <fullName>Sen. McCaskill, Claire [D-MO]</fullName>
            <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
            <middleName />
            <firstName>Claire</firstName>
            <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
          </item>
          <item>
            <party>R</party>
            <sponsorshipDate>2015-12-16</sponsorshipDate>
            <bioguideId>J000293</bioguideId>
            <state>WI</state>
            <lastName>Johnson</lastName>
            <identifiers>
              <lisID>2086</lisID>
              <bioguideId>J000293</bioguideId>
              <gpoId>8355</gpoId>
            </identifiers>
            <fullName>Sen. Johnson, Ron [R-WI]</fullName>
            <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
            <middleName />
            <firstName>Ron</firstName>
            <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
          </item>
        </cosponsors>
        <createDate>2015-12-17T09:59:01Z</createDate>
        <type>SAMDT</type>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <version>1.0.0</version>
        <description />
        <links />
        <number>2930</number>
        <updateDate>2017-06-02T19:12:28Z</updateDate>
        <notes />
        <proposedDate>2015-12-16T05:00:00Z</proposedDate>
        <actions>
          <count>6</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
              <committee />
              <links>
                <link>
                  <name>S.Amdt.2930</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/114th-congress/senate-amendment/2930</url>
                </link>
                <link>
                  <name>SA 2930</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/114th-congress/senate-amendment/2930</url>
                </link>
              </links>
              <sourceSystem>
                <name>Senate</name>
                <code>0</code>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 2930 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
              <committee />
              <links>
                <link>
                  <name>S.Amdt.2930</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/114th-congress/senate-amendment/2930</url>
                </link>
                <link>
                  <name>S8728-8729</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-161/senate-section/page/S8728-8729</url>
                </link>
                <link>
                  <name>SA 2930</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/114th-congress/senate-amendment/2930</url>
                </link>
              </links>
              <sourceSystem>
                <name>Senate</name>
                <code>0</code>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 2930 proposed by Senator McConnell for Senator Carper. (consideration: CR S8728-8729; text: CR S8728-8729)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
              <committee />
              <links />
              <text />
            </item>
            <item>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 2930 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <sourceSystem>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
                <code>9</code>
              </sourceSystem>
              <actionCode>94000</actionCode>
              <links>
                <link>
                  <name>S.Amdt.2930</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/114th-congress/senate-amendment/2930</url>
                </link>
                <link>
                  <name>SA 2930</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/114th-congress/senate-amendment/2930</url>
                </link>
              </links>
              <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
              <committee />
            </item>
            <item>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2930 proposed by Senator McConnell for Senator Carper.</text>
              <sourceSystem>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
                <code>9</code>
              </sourceSystem>
              <actionCode>93000</actionCode>
              <links>
                <link>
                  <name>S.Amdt.2930</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/114th-congress/senate-amendment/2930</url>
                </link>
                <link>
                  <name>S8728-8729</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-161/senate-section/page/S8728-8729</url>
                </link>
                <link>
                  <name>SA 2930</name>
                  <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/114th-congress/senate-amendment/2930</url>
                </link>
              </links>
              <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
              <committee />
            </item>
            <item>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
              <sourceSystem>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
                <code>9</code>
              </sourceSystem>
              <actionCode>91000</actionCode>
              <links />
              <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
              <committee />
            </item>
          </actions>
          <actionByCounts>
            <senate>5</senate>
          </actionByCounts>
          <actionTypeCounts>
            <senateAmendmentAgreedTo>1</senateAmendmentAgreedTo>
            <senateAmendmentSubmitted>1</senateAmendmentSubmitted>
            <senateAmendmentProposedOnTheFloor>1</senateAmendmentProposedOnTheFloor>
            <amendmentAgreedTo>1</amendmentAgreedTo>
            <amendmentProposed>1</amendmentProposed>
          </actionTypeCounts>
        </actions>
        <amendedBill>
          <title>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</title>
          <congress>114</congress>
          <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
          <number>1616</number>
          <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
          <type>S</type>
        </amendedBill>
      </amendment>
    </amendments>
    <updateDate>2017-06-02T23:13:00Z</updateDate>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
          <actionDate>2016-07-21</actionDate>
        </latestAction>
        <latestTitle>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2016</latestTitle>
        <number>5922</number>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

