<bill session="114" type="h" number="6072" updated="2017-06-02T22:15:42Z">
  <state datetime="2016-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Election Integrity Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to promote accuracy, integrity, and security in the administration of elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Election Integrity Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2016-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2016-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412616" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2016-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412606" joined="2016-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2016-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2016-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2016-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2016-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2016-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY15" subcommittee="Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1617"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="3309"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-09-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Election Integrity Act of 2016

This bill amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to: (1) prohibit states or jurisdictions from purchasing or otherwise acquiring for use in an election for federal office a direct recording electronic voting system or other electronic voting system that does not produce a voter-verified paper record; (2) prohibit imposition of conditions on voting by mail; (3) make mandatory the availability of early voting; and (4) require sufficient polling places, equipment, and resources to facilitate voting.

The Director of the National Science Foundation shall make grants to eligible entities to study, test, and develop accessible ballot voting, verification, and casting mechanisms and devices and best practices to enhance the accessibility of paper ballot voting and verification mechanisms for individuals with disabilities, for voters whose primary language is not English, and for voters with difficulties in literacy.

Each state shall, except when the winning candidate had no opponent or received 80% or more of the votes, administer audits of federal election results, without advance notice to the precincts selected, consisting of random hand counts of the voter-verified paper ballots.

This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to make it unlawful for a chief state election administration official, unless he or she or a family member is a candidate, to take an active part in political management or in a political campaign for federal office over which such official has supervisory authority.

Mandatory response by the Attorney General is required to allegations of voter intimidation or suppression by law enforcement officers and other government officials.

The Election Assistance Commission shall study and, on the basis of the findings of the study, issue standards for states to follow in establishing an appropriate number and geographic distribution of voting sites in elections for federal office.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
